[{"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aef", "question": "What is a \"dhampir\"?", "answer": "A half human, half vampire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339927", "question": "In what film does Jack Nicholson famously say, \u201cHeeeeere\u2019s Johnny!\u201d?", "answer": "The Shining", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c771", "question": "The Plato Scale is used specifically in the making of what beverage?", "answer": "Beer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a677", "question": "Which US state was named after the King of France?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c89", "question": "What 1972 comedy begins with \"Once upon a time there was a plaid overnight bag\"?", "answer": "What's Up Doc?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f6f03a9e54d890926f6cd", "question": "What country is home to the world's most rapidly-constructed skyscraper?", "answer": "China -- Broad Sustainable Building company built a 57-story building called Mini Sky City in 19 days using prefab components.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389f5", "question": "Which Paul McCartney and Wings album includes \"Picasso's Last Words\"?", "answer": "Band on the Run", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7761feec85e375820b317", "question": "Where is the Valley of the Moon?", "answer": "Jordan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59da1b9ff6756c9b30ba14fb", "question": "Kiev is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Ukraine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c9b49076251badbead8", "question": "Who was the first American to orbit the Earth?", "answer": "John Glenn -- He orbited the Earth three times in five hours in a Mercury space capsule he named \"Friendship 7\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe698dc20565ad31a57c73c", "question": "What singers lure sailors to crash on the rocks with their songs?", "answer": "Sirens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c998", "question": "Caries refers to decay in what?", "answer": "Teeth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b6991dde762b54eb9be941d", "question": "What famous statue was discovered in 1820 on the Greek island of Milos?", "answer": "Venus de Milo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b454", "question": "Where did Abraham Lincoln give his historic speech?", "answer": "Gettysburg, Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a25eec56682715b82711cd0", "question": "What year did Spain start to colonize Venezuela?", "answer": "1522", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a0", "question": "What is Demeter the goddess of?", "answer": "Harvest and agriculture", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e4", "question": "What chemical element is added to rubber to \"vulcanize\" it?", "answer": "Sulfur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c07d", "question": "What is hippophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Horses", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0db", "question": "What Tennessee university was the first college to field a men's basketball team, in 1893?", "answer": "Vanderbilt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae53", "question": "What was the name given to the first German democracy established in 1919?", "answer": "Weimar Republic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdc16a0469bb8041d07a08d", "question": "What is the Japanese word for \"dog\"?", "answer": "Inu", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c6", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering inert gases?", "answer": "William Ramsey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef63736ce05a3942286e64", "question": "Who was the first woman to host an American late night show?", "answer": "Joan Rivers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdffd141cf6db9ac4808d08", "question": "Which country built an airport that only landed one commercial aircraft?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e07", "question": "What 1993 movie's title character is actually out-of-work voice actor Daniel Hillard?", "answer": "Mrs. Doubtfire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e7", "question": "What company produced the first computer to run a Microsoft operating system?", "answer": "IBM", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c96", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Norwich, Vermont?", "answer": "Newhart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d7", "question": "What Canadian city was Mill Street beer originally brewed in?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25e", "question": "What is a wallaby?", "answer": "A kangaroo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e6", "question": "What year was carbon 14 first discovered?", "answer": "1940", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fb", "question": "Who was the first Canadian-born boxer to win the heavyweight championship?", "answer": "Tommy Burns", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a584", "question": "Which US state's name is derived from the Chippewa words for \"great water\"?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a25f", "question": "What is Jane Fonda's middle name?", "answer": "Seymour", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cf16bb53d1af658864f2", "question": "Who does an angel placed on top of the Christmas tree represent?", "answer": "Archangel Gabriel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b32a", "question": "Florence Nightingale tended the soldiers in which war?", "answer": "Crimean", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4ded806d333868d34d71c", "question": "Who was the first Western explorer to reach China?", "answer": "Marco Polo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caaf", "question": "What is a Kissing gourami?", "answer": "Tropical fish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab960b86faa38a764be51b", "question": "What former republic did the Trabant originate from?", "answer": "East Germany, or German Democratic Republic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f35", "question": "Who titled his 1989 autobiography \"Holy Cow!\"?", "answer": "Harry Caray", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59636ac3967692ea851899a0", "question": "Which two cross-border neighbouring cities jointly celebrate July 1 and July 4 holidays with the International Freedom Festival?", "answer": "Windsor and Detroit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abfb", "question": "Which river is often viewed as Russia's national river?", "answer": "Volga", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f66", "question": "What is \"bountiful mother\" in Latin?", "answer": "Alma mater", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac91", "question": "Which Egyptian queen is said to have died following a bite from an asp?", "answer": "Cleopatra", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c288", "question": "What term applies to space devoid of matter?", "answer": "Vacuum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b2a4e662d71a53650fdb", "question": "What are the first names of Lord Voldemort's parents?", "answer": "Tom and Merope", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6018bc34d96d05b23b281654", "question": "In which country did Buddhism originate?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae01", "question": "King Zog ruled which country?", "answer": "Albania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b56f", "question": "What is the Comprehensive Environmental Response Compensation and Liability Act (CERCLA) known as?", "answer": "Superfund", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bd8bd96d05b23b28165c", "question": "Atropos, Lachesis, and Clotho are the Three what of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Fates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ec", "question": "Musophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Mice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a6", "question": "What color is the supposedly cursed Hope Diamond?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d0", "question": "Which Hans Christian Andersen fairy tale figure sits by the waterside in Copenhagen?", "answer": "The Little Mermaid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff512ccff04d658268c92d4", "question": "The Great Leap Forward in China was primarily designed to do what?", "answer": "A campaign aimed to transform the country from an agrarian economy into a socialist society through\u00a0rapid industrialization.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00d", "question": "What was the real first name of David Soul's \"Hutch\" on \"Starsky and Hutch\"?", "answer": "Ken", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a3126c0f9723ab15cb49", "question": "What was the first department store?", "answer": "Harding, Howell and Company Grand Fashionable Magazine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9d0", "question": "In nautical terms, what does \"Port\" mean?", "answer": "Left", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0fc", "question": "Who created Gomez, Mortia and Uncle Fester as a cartoon?", "answer": "Charles Addams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b311", "question": "Peter the Great is considered the founding father of what country?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abae", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Maryland?", "answer": "Annapolis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ec", "question": "What musical instrument appears on the Guinness beer label?", "answer": "Harp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c074", "question": "What is the regulation height for a pin in Ten Pin bowling?", "answer": "Fifteen inches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab28", "question": "Antananarivo is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a379", "question": "What is the capital of Spain?", "answer": "Madrid", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac79", "question": "During which American period did stock car racing gain most of its popularity?", "answer": "The Prohibition", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa1", "question": "What actress originated the role of Mame in the musical \"Mame\"?", "answer": "Angela Lansbury", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600244b84be4723ccac221a7", "question": "What artist drew the comic strip Bloom County from 1980 to 1989?", "answer": "\"Bloom County\"\u00a0is a comic strip by\u00a0Berkeley Breathed\u00a0which examines events in politics and culture in small-town Middle America.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b13ce662d71a53650fcf", "question": "What is the name of the train station that services Hogwarts School?", "answer": "Hogsmeade Station", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8af", "question": "Luna orbits what planet of the solar system?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae1b", "question": "In which decade did the Wall Street crash lead to the Great Depression?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a1e1d75b5a031299b74573b", "question": "The Okapi is native to which African country?", "answer": "Congo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd8c", "question": "What ingredient appears alongside potatoes in the Indian dish aloo gobi?", "answer": "Cauliflower", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed4", "question": "What SNL cast member voiced \"Waldo\" in Van Halen's \"Hot for Teacher\" video?", "answer": "Phil Hartman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a7", "question": "Who played Mad Max Rockatansky?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2de", "question": "How many flowers must honeybees visit to make one pound of honey?", "answer": "2 Million", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a557", "question": "Which four US states share a border with Oregon?", "answer": "California, Idaho, Nevada, Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339300", "question": "What song does Ferris Bueller sing from the float in the Chicago parade?", "answer": "Twist and Shout", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590721263745b36be73039f5", "question": "Who played the role of Kris Kringle in the 1947 film \"Miracle on 34th Street\"?", "answer": "Edmund Gwenn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d4", "question": "What geological period followed the Jurassic?", "answer": "Cretaceous", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af2566fb63e5727cf5a483d", "question": "Before gaining international popularity with its plastic interlocking bricks, what did Lego make?", "answer": "Wooden toys", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef59c46ce05a3942286e06", "question": "Who was the first Western music artist(s) to be allowed to perform a concert in China?", "answer": "Wham! Wham!'s 1985 visit to and concerts in China were both firsts by a Western pop act in that country.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c715", "question": "What vegetable gets its name from the Latin word for \"branch\"?", "answer": "Broccoli", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede4566ce05a3942286ddc", "question": "In what country did Mia Hamm learn to play soccer?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394df", "question": "What was the name of the family in \"One Man's Family\" TV show?", "answer": "The Barbours", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c4", "question": "In the sitcom, \"Only Fools and Horses\" what is Rodney's middle name?", "answer": "Charlton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b57185367df192a942e335d", "question": "The \"Strait of Magellan\" is part of which continent?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a5", "question": "What famous landmark is located in Agra, India?", "answer": "Taj Mahal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067ca2ff9c0647b50a806e", "question": "What virtual reality set was launched in March, 2016?", "answer": "Occulus Rift", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c19a877e98cb97778978", "question": "Which French landmark is known for its red windmill?", "answer": "Moulin Rouge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133901d", "question": "Sidney Paget is famous for creating the visual image of which literary character?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bfe00b8b668d7dfe168b5c5", "question": "What is the ruling planet of the astrological sign Taurus?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e147f3f6ca6dac04a20ca53", "question": "The Harry Nilsson song \"Gotta Get Up\" was frequently used in which Netflix original series?", "answer": "Russian Doll", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d6", "question": "Which countries does France share a land border with?", "answer": "Spain, Luxembourg, Belgium, Switzerland, Monaco, Andorra, Germany and Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b358ba05db0d66a186cb558", "question": "In architecture, what is a \"Purlin\"?", "answer": "A horizontal structural member", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe25690658e585fda9cfa37", "question": "The holiday of Christmas is celebrated in what month by Eastern Orthodox churches?", "answer": "January", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b4e1e662d71a53650ff1", "question": "Which of Edgar Allen Poe's works was written in honor of his wife?", "answer": "Annabel Lee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd81c98d0de9af39e9d4686", "question": "What U.S. president was nicknamed \"Napoleon of the Stump?\"", "answer": "James K. Polk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f6fb1a9e54d890926f6d2", "question": "Which country is home to the colorful Rainbow Mountain?", "answer": "Peru -- AKA Vinicunca, it achieves its vibrant hues thanks to natural weathering, which has exposed mineral strips in the earth.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5954e76b8e82ccaf3b9a67ba", "question": "What do male lions do about 20 hours a day?", "answer": "Sleep", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f44", "question": "\"Pee-Wee's Big Adventure\" is to recover what beloved stolen item?", "answer": "His bike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac77", "question": "When was the modern tire first introduced to the market?", "answer": "1887", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a88c", "question": "The seismic belt called the Ring of Fire surrounds what body of water?", "answer": "The Pacific Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef93fe6ce05a3942286e93", "question": "What show did \"TV Guide\" name the \"best TV show of all time\" in 2002?", "answer": "\"Seinfeld\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b51e", "question": "What gives Tonic Water its flavour?", "answer": "Quinine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4fa", "question": "What two US state names end with the letter Y?", "answer": "Kentucky and New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133944e", "question": "How many times did Peter Sellers play Inspector Clouseau?", "answer": "Six", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600399ab57a0e35c43f8389e", "question": "What artist first achieved notoriety through graffiti epigrams?", "answer": "Jean-Michel Basquiat\u00a0first achieved notoriety as part of SAMO, an informal graffiti duo who wrote enigmatic epigrams.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca13", "question": "What is a group of snipe called?", "answer": "A wisp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cbe", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional \"The Stonecutters\" fraternity?", "answer": "The Simpsons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b1", "question": "What was Aerosmith\u2019s first Top 10 song on the Billboard charts?", "answer": "Dream On", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdec", "question": "What was the first Major League Baseball team to play in a stadium with a fully retractable roof?", "answer": "The Toronto Blue Jays", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339520", "question": "What does Mahoney teach Hightower to do in the movie \"Policy Academy\"?", "answer": "Drive", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe765feeec85e375820b27b", "question": "Which mountain range is home to the largest U.S. National Park?", "answer": "Saint Elias Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca40", "question": "What is inflammation of the gums called?", "answer": "Gingivitis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d9", "question": "What name is given to the line running across a snooker table?", "answer": "Balk line", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b293", "question": "What European country ruled Macau until December 20, 1999?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b20f", "question": "Who was assassinated by Leon Czolgosz?", "answer": "William McKinley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f517ff048f679a45aad1", "question": "Noctiphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Night", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b77b", "question": "What 1990's fad involved something known as a slammer?", "answer": "Pogs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339090", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was the god of the underworld?", "answer": "Hades", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e72c999d0874f1a5e2d1c1e", "question": "What famous suffragette was born Araminta Ross?", "answer": "Harriet Tubman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8d36ec223966ae8f8850", "question": "Which NBA personality actually owns the term \"three-peat\", referring to a team winning three consecutive championships?", "answer": "Pat Riley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a9", "question": "How many US state capital cities lie on the Mississippi River?", "answer": "Two - Baton Rouge and St. Paul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e482fe83fe1f2a824bb5", "question": "In the last six months of the war, what was the U.S. strategy for winning the conflict with Japan?", "answer": "Break the Japanese will with massive bombing raids on Japanese cities", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934e", "question": "Who played Alex's sister, Mallory, on the TV show \"Family Ties\"?", "answer": "Justine Bateman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff7bc0b2b316f4693fb678a", "question": "What is a wainwright?", "answer": "A wainwright, also known as cartwright, is someone who repairs wagons and carts.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a8", "question": "What song is most famous for its suggestive chorus of \"Voulez-vous coucher avec moi (ce soir)\"?", "answer": "Lady Marmalade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b40", "question": "Which items are melting in Salvador Dali's painting \"The Persistence of Memory\"?", "answer": "Watches", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ccf7b6cb37b32637bdc44c5", "question": "Which major river is adjacent to Memphis, Egypt?", "answer": "The Nile River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5989a867cb8751d53e7d75fa", "question": "United States' observation of Mardi Gras was started in which city and state?", "answer": "Mobile, Alabama", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e58", "question": "What literary work inspired Nirvana's \"Scentless Apprentice\" song?", "answer": "Perfume", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e5", "question": "What game was invented when Winnie-the-Pooh accidentally dropped a fir cone off a bridge?", "answer": "Poohsticks", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5b0", "question": "What 2 planets in the solar system are typically synonymous with the man and woman?", "answer": "Mars and Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98d", "question": "What part of a piano's action permits the keys to be struck in quick repetition?", "answer": "Escapement", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339992", "question": "How many episodes of \"The Cosby Show\" were made?", "answer": "197", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeaf", "question": "Which leader\u2019s statue was pulled down from it\u2019s place in red Square in 1991?", "answer": "Lenin's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb54b65ff7d326b622a90", "question": "In Shakespeare's play \"Titus Andronicus\", who is Titus' daughter?", "answer": "Lavinia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c90d0ee52800b05cac20f0f", "question": "What is Eisoptrophobia?", "answer": "The fear of mirrors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdda", "question": "Ash Wednesday marks the first day of what?", "answer": "Lent", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf9a", "question": "In the standard game of Scrabble, what is the value of the letters \"Q\" and \"Z\"?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab64", "question": "From what country did the US buy the Virgin Islands?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e5f0cc2d274615ecf514531", "question": "Which Great Lake was known by the Ojibway as \"great water\"?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae33", "question": "When did the War of 1812 actually begin?", "answer": "1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfcf", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"S\"?", "answer": "Sierra", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab06", "question": "What was Genghis Khan's birth name?", "answer": "Temujin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e6", "question": "What was the first NASA program to land an object on Mars that sent information back to Earth?", "answer": "Viking", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e32cfe83fe1f2a824ba8", "question": "What was the significance of Guadalcanal to Japan?", "answer": "The island was in an ideal position for controlling the Solomon Islands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf14", "question": "Who rode Shergar to victory in the Epsom Derby?", "answer": "Walter Swinburn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedda276ce05a3942286d82", "question": "What is the first thing Andy seeks to get in prison in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Andy asks Red to get him a rock hammer.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a82d", "question": "What is the capital of Cambodia?", "answer": "Phnom Penh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a29d", "question": "Who starred as the male lead in the Alfred Hitchcock film \"To Catch a Thief\"?", "answer": "Cary Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe775fbeec85e375820b314", "question": "What constellation appears on the Alaskan flag?", "answer": "Ursa Major", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff13f6eb0ee8c595b6d398f", "question": "Who wrote 1818\u2019s \"Frankenstein\"?", "answer": "Mary Shelley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69a4c20565ad31a57c752", "question": "Plato thought the Lost Island of Atlantis was linked to which ancient culture?", "answer": "Minoan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a387", "question": "What is the capital of Iceland?", "answer": "Reykjavik", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59cdb1ff65ff7d326b622a6f", "question": "Petrology the study of what?", "answer": "Rocks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe73377eec85e375820b221", "question": "What was the name of the antisemitic laws passed in Nazi Germany on September 15, 1935?", "answer": "Nuremberg Law", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a33", "question": "What do sisters Elinor and Marianne Dashwood represent in the title of a Jane Austen novel?", "answer": "Sense and Sensibility", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb3f", "question": "How many squares are on a checker board?", "answer": "64", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388eb", "question": "What is the dot in the \"i\" called?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53f", "question": "What letter is least used in the English language?", "answer": "Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdac", "question": "What are the only two ingredients allowed in the \"host\", the Catholic Communion wafer?", "answer": "Wheat flower and water", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab2f", "question": "Which ocean is the region of Melanesia located in?", "answer": "Pacific", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aee", "question": "In Greek mythology, what is the name of the god of Dreams?", "answer": "Morpheus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea82e4ff048f679a45ac24", "question": "How many zeros are in a quadrillion?", "answer": "15", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b1d", "question": "Who played Gilligan on \"Gilligan's Island\"?", "answer": "Bob Denver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133989a", "question": "What dancer from Omaha was born Fred Austerlitz?", "answer": "Fred Astaire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf2", "question": "In which city was the composer Ludwig Van Beethoven born?", "answer": "Bonn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8ac8101dd7bf43be5e76c", "question": "Which common houseplant is said to make burns heal faster?", "answer": "Aloe Vera", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a277", "question": "When was actress and pin-up model, Betty Grable born?", "answer": "1916", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a157", "question": "The character of Mike Myers features heavily in which series of horror movies?", "answer": "Halloween", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0fb", "question": "What major political scandal of the Harding administration involved a naval oil reserve on public land in Wyoming?", "answer": "The Teapot Dome Scandal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d9", "question": "How many US states are named after a president?", "answer": "One - Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be89", "question": "What type of a tree killed Jackson Pollock?", "answer": "Oak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe938516bd93ce3a4e5f683", "question": "Koinoniphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Rooms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb40", "question": "What color is the 4-ball in a game of pool?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ba", "question": "Which river is often viewed as Russia's national river?", "answer": "Volga", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4ae449076251badbeabd", "question": "Who earned the nickname \"Moses\" in the Underground Railroad?", "answer": "Harriet Tubman -- One of the most well-known coordinators of the Underground Railroad, she helped more than 70 slaves to freedom.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5902a089cad1ec93f27df76d", "question": "What color is pure caffeine?", "answer": "White", "category": "Science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd0e", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal whose mascot was Cornelius?", "answer": "Kellogg's Corn Flakes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3cd", "question": "What country is sometimes called the Land of Fire and Ice?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa3a", "question": "What is the capital of Barbados?", "answer": "Bridgetown", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396eb", "question": "On the Academy Awards statue, what is Oscar standing on?", "answer": "A reel of film", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339edb", "question": "What position was first held by Steve Allen?", "answer": "Tonight Show host", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b1", "question": "What did the band The Clash rock?", "answer": "The Casbah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b9", "question": "What is measured in Watts?", "answer": "Power", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fffa83373838c5c8a417f3b", "question": "Which dinosaur had 15 horns?", "answer": "Kosmoceratops", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8af", "question": "In what city would you find Centennial Olympic Park?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b4", "question": "In which country will you find most of the Aral sea in?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca5c", "question": "The flowers of the curry tree are what color?", "answer": "White", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca52", "question": "What is the more common name for the fruit \"Citrus maxima\"?", "answer": "Pomelo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb3", "question": "Robert Plant was the lead singer for what rock band from 1968 to 1980?", "answer": "Led Zeppelin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a51b", "question": "On which sea does Romania have a coastline?", "answer": "Black Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c021", "question": "Which fashion designer was shot dead in the summer of 1997?", "answer": "Gianni Versace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008aafcf842fa4c4ba9692", "question": "Who released the 1979 song \"Rock 'n' Roll High School\"?", "answer": "The Ramones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339181", "question": "Who was the female lead character in the movie \"Three Colors: White\"?", "answer": "Julie Delpy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35b", "question": "What is a \"kartoffel\" in Hamburg?", "answer": "A potato", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339158", "question": "What popular artist sang the words: \"I'm afraid of Americans\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4da", "question": "Which is larger, a baseball or a softball?", "answer": "A softball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a71", "question": "What is the name of the milkman in \"Fiddler on the Roof\"?", "answer": "Tevye", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59067a13ff9c0647b50a8053", "question": "What is the United Kingdom European Union membership referendum of 2016, more widely known as?", "answer": "Brexit", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf63", "question": "How is rockstar Vincent Furnier better known?", "answer": "Alice Cooper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be61", "question": "Avian flu in China led to 2006 price hikes in what piece of sporting equipment?", "answer": "Badminton birdies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de4", "question": "In the TV show \"Twin Peaks\", what letter was found under Laura Palmer's fingernail?", "answer": "R", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60173fab44491cbd7c5a17b4", "question": "What general commanded the American Expeditionary Forces on the Western Front during World War I?", "answer": "John Joseph \"Black Jack\" Pershing GCB", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d4", "question": "On the ph scale, what number indicates neutrality?", "answer": "7", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9d1", "question": "In nautical terms, what does \"Starboard\" mean?", "answer": "Right", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb61c15dad637d903c8830", "question": "Bammy is a traditional Jamaican bread made primarily of what?", "answer": "Cassava flour", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e4a", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Action Jackson\"?", "answer": "Carl Weathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd662c7a5bfecdd737e0848", "question": "What was Princess Diana's title before she married Prince Charles?", "answer": "Lady Diana Spencer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c652", "question": "What sense is most closely linked to memory?", "answer": "Smell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4dcf306d333868d34d6fd", "question": "Who won four gold medals in the 1936 Olympics, infuriating Adolf Hitler?", "answer": "Jessie Owens", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff6719f52a821ff76ae8b25", "question": "Which popular tea blend is named for a British Prime Minister?", "answer": "Earl Grey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b36e121c3f17ccc40c8e08", "question": "What common household object appears in the opening scene of the film \"The Sixth Sense\"?", "answer": "A light bulb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b08d", "question": "The British passed the Intolerable Acts as punishment for what act by the American colonists?", "answer": "The Boston Tea Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600780f8bd51d85e222ab646", "question": "What is the main visual element in Impressionist painting?", "answer": "They were interested in trying to capture the changing effects of light by using a more exact analysis of tone and color.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c517877e98cb977789aa", "question": "What London landmark is protected by six ravens?", "answer": "Tower of London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ca", "question": "What letter is displayed on a typical hot-water tap in France?", "answer": "C", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d4", "question": "What is the atomic number of iodine?", "answer": "53", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ec", "question": "What is the technical name of the pound sign?", "answer": "Octothorpe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339918", "question": "What was the name of the hotel in the 1960 movie \"Psycho\"?", "answer": "Bates Motel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e6", "question": "What US state has been led by Harold Stassen and Jesse Ventura?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe3e8ec38e4e5d4832e630d", "question": "What year was the battle of Bannockburn fought between the English and the Scots?", "answer": "1314", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a818", "question": "After Central Park was completed, New York City's 4th Avenue, above 32nd Street, was renamed what?", "answer": "Park Avenue", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e97", "question": "What baseball player titled his memoir \"Wizard\"?", "answer": "Ozzie Smith", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5cd40de9685cf15b733e9895", "question": "What is Xenoglossophobia?", "answer": "The fear of learning or using foreign languages", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b960", "question": "Excluding the Umpires, how many players take part at the same time in a game of cricket?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ae", "question": "In what city would you find Gorky Park?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a034", "question": "In the show \"Family Guy\", which US president has been seen happily singing in public about being nude?", "answer": "Bill Clinton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c86b877e98cb977789e4", "question": "Where can you see the petroglyphs of Newspaper Rock?", "answer": "Petrified Forrest National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a645", "question": "Which US state is known as the \"Land of Lincoln\"?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a6", "question": "Zoologist Dian Fossey dedicated her life to the study of what animals?", "answer": "Gorillas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133902d", "question": "Which English word is a combination of the first 2 letters of the Greek alphabet?", "answer": "Alphabet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a69b", "question": "What was Namibia formerly called?", "answer": "South-West Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5904a0decf93664eb10486bb", "question": "The \"Ugu Youth\" radio station is broadcast in which African country?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bee", "question": "What year did singer Cherilyn Sarkisian La Piere Bono Allman legally change her name to just Cher?", "answer": "1978", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c94dfbde8045e48466ea", "question": "Why do pigs roll around in the mud?", "answer": "To cool down -- Pigs have very few sweat glands, so they must roll in mud to stay cool and prevent sunburns.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d5c", "question": "What year was the first \"Twilight\" novel published in?", "answer": "2005", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8b", "question": "What settlers introduced gingerbread houses to Canada in the 1700's?", "answer": "German settlers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede07e6ce05a3942286db9", "question": "What's the dog's name in \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Max", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a589", "question": "Which present day US state did Ponce De Leon explore?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c511", "question": "What are deheaded, deveined and sorted by size in a Laitram machine?", "answer": "Shrimp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969e", "question": "Who played the role of Peachy Carnehan in the 1975 movie \"The Man Who Would Be King\"?", "answer": "Michael Caine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5ed26ce05a3942286e3a", "question": "What baseball legend has a cameo in \"The Benchwarmers\"?", "answer": "Reggie Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9a0", "question": "What is -459.67 F also know as?", "answer": "Absolute Zero", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d3d", "question": "What actor died nine days after completing his final movie \"Soylent Green\"?", "answer": "Edward G. Robinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae8641c7f28483af1e7fdcd", "question": "In which year did India gain its independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1947", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b54e", "question": "What does CMYK stand for in colour printing?", "answer": "Cyan, Magenta, Yellow, Key Black", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f3", "question": "What was John Wayne\u2019s nickname?", "answer": "The Duke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cb70cdcf96e155acab35d30", "question": "What country once technically fought a war against a species of bird?", "answer": "Australia, \"The Emu War\"", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecd54fec223966ae8f88cf", "question": "What TV show won the most Emmys in 2018?", "answer": "The Marvelous Mrs. Maisel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca82", "question": "What type of fat was margarine first made from in the U.S.?", "answer": "Beef", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a987", "question": "What city named its airport after Louis Armstrong?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f42", "question": "Who created the character of Yogi Bear?", "answer": "William Hanna and Joseph Barbera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e1f", "question": "What artist sold only one painting, \"The Red Vineyard\", during his lifetime?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}]